[Music]
it's the fastest most extreme and most
exclusive production super sports car in
the world the French made vehicle shoots
along the road at a top speed of 420
kilometers an hour this hyper car
scratches at the boundaries of physics a
motorized superlative it is this
ambivalence between beauty and beast to
awaken the beast in this ultra powerful
engineering work of art the developers
have made the best even better I think
you start working where others have
stopped the mission a hyper sports car
with 1500 horsepower and a top speed of
420 kilometers an hour that the whole
world said you'll never manage to cram
so much power in a car the whole world
was wrong but the enormous power
concealed in this rocket poses new
challenges
you have to be sure that you've still
got enough white on the front that it
won't take off to ensure a healthy body
mass index the Alsace engineers have
fitted the all-wheel drive vehicle with
lots of carbon titanium and magnesium
potential lots of things you would
normally only find in Formula one cars
and the elegant top athlete with the 16
cylinder engine is anything but normal
the design engineers all agree about
that but my nature can you compare the
sheer on with another vehicle no God
created heaven and earth and the French
created the bugatti shear on the
spearhead of vehicle construction is
located in multi france the bugatti
hyper sports car manufacturer these
record-holding dream cars have been
built on the site of the former family
estate for the past 110 years built in
2004 in the form of a company logo the
Alsatians lovingly refer to the new
production building as the Dream Factory
inside 20 employees assemble up to 16
vehicles at the same time at 12 stations
with these production figures Bugatti is
part of the ort Keturah
among vehicle manufacturers the bugatti
chiron is the flagship of the current
collection
it's a lot of manual work it's like in a
Formula One racing stable everything's
handmade at various stations yeah I some
300 people work at Bugatti engineers
sales representatives and purchasers I
encode for people who share a passion us
to develop build and sell super sports
cars weekend Subhan
once offical fini it takes two months
until the French have assembled around
2,600 individual parts to form a new
motorsport work of art
the Sheeran's hood conceals pure
performance the world's most powerful
production engine has 16 cylinders and a
displacement of 8 litres this enables
the Bugatti to reach its record-breaking
speed of 420 kilometers an hour for
offset operating turbochargers
accelerate the 1500 horsepower
projectile from zero to a hundred
kilometers an hour in just 2.4 seconds
instead of a classic production line
there are four special stations in
Molsheim they each contain two
independent lifting platforms because
the sports coupe a is made up of two
parts which the employees marry with one
another during production three
mechanics always assemble what is called
the Sheeran's
rolling chassis strictly by hand the
drivable naked vehicle skeleton
[Applause]
an expensive delivery is waiting at the
Bugatti cargo ramp this body component
heralds the construction of a new
all-wheel-drive behemoth the monocoque
is a hollow driver cockpit and is made
entirely of carbon fiber reinforced
plastic or CFRP for steel journals now
rise up out of the gleaming shop floor
two workers install an assembly platform
on them the production crew then heaves
the 150 kilogram carbon framework onto
the platform each material that the
bugatti design engineers install fulfils
a specific purpose the materials we use
at Bugatti are the finest but also the
lightest available we used lots of
magnesium titanium carbon and aluminum
lots of things that you would normally
only find in Formula one cars don't I
think there are no miracles and
Technology our bugatti chiron is capable
of topping 400 kilometres per hour and
can accelerate from zero to 100 in less
than three seconds we're talking about
numbers and performance that are somehow
unreal means that this simply represents
a lot of work at the development and
also at the production level to ensure
this performance is always achieved the
technicians install the wiring harness
inside the carbon cockpit the harness
consists of 2.5 kilometres of cables and
is the nerve system of the shiron it
connects the vehicles 20 control units
the mechanics fastened the electrical
wires to the monocoque with titanium
screws like all of the other elements in
this racing machine the wiring harness
is also designed as compact and light as
possible
the rear frame of the exclusive kupe is
assembled on the second platform
but first the workers move the assembly
frame to the heart of the bugatti the
640 kilograms 16 cylinder engine due to
the size and the enormous weight of this
unit the assembly platform comes to the
engine in Molsheim the mechanics use a
crane to put the german-built
high-performance powerplant down on the
assembly platform
the engines are manufactured at the
Volkswagen engine plant in SATs katha
covering 2.8 million square meters this
site boasts its own bugatti department
whoever works here belongs to the
absolute elite among engine mechanics as
the 16 cylinder is considered to be the
holy grail of engines two technicians
need one week to build one of the 1500
horsepower quad turbo engines your mock
we built a car that does over 400
kilometres an hour and drives elegantly
to the Opera in the evenings to do this
you need not only a car that can achieve
this but also an engine that's capable
of driving in the summer and winter in
cities traffic jams as well as on
racetracks and that's something of a
challenge for the Formula One teams are
good at building racing engines with
lots of power and Volkswagen is adept at
building good engines for the road for a
golf but this combination of two worlds
is Bugatti specialty
[Music]
christened production nests by the
technicians the four workplaces in the
engine department are also special each
station is structured so that a complete
unit can be built here the experts
manufacture a total of three of these
powerful heavy weights per week
to make the engine as compact as
possible eight cylinders are distributed
over each of the two v-shaped banks thus
creating an artificial W engine with 16
cylinders the W 16 achieves its maximum
acceleration with for high-performance
turbochargers via turbine the quartet
compresses the air in taken at the front
of the vehicle and presses it into the
combustion chamber in stages thanks to
what Bugatti calls sequential turbo
charging turbo 3 and 4 cut in at 2,800
rpm this prevents turbo lag and
therefore ensures constant power at
production nest to a new crankcase is
ready to be assembled a mechanic has
just installed the Pistons in the 16
cylinders and connected them to the
crankshaft before the engine builders
continue their work they use an
electronic torque wrench to simulate
engine operation for instance this
allows the workers to check that the
piston stroke does not lead to friction
on the cylinder wall otherwise serious
engine damage called piston seizure
could occur later while driving
the Sheeran's engine is made up of
around 3,700 individual parts the
technicians pre-assemble individual
components at workplaces next to the
assembly stand this worker is assembling
various engine elements here he is
fitting a fuel pump later on it will
deliver the required quantity of fuel to
the engine the worker then installs the
alternator its task is to generate
electricity for the starter battery and
other electrical components
at the same time his colleague prepares
the oil pan for assembly it has to be
absolutely leak tight because later on
the pan contains the engine oil needed
to lubricate the 16 cylinder engine this
is why the technician now takes it to an
automatic station two different
processes take place here first a
special oxygen plasma cleans the surface
of the pan
although the engineers pay strict
attention to cleanliness there is still
a fine layer of dirt on the components
the station then applies a black sealant
onto the edge of the magnesium pan once
the sealant has been completely
distributed the technician has 20
minutes to assemble the component to do
this he positions the oil pan over the
crankshaft onto the lower side of the
engine block and seals it
only specially trained technicians are
permitted to build the Sheerin engine
whoever has successfully completed the
additional two-year training can
justifiably feel proud I'm one of a
total of eight technicians worldwide who
are permitted to build this engine in
series of course that makes you very
proud it's like you made your hobby your
vocation you can already get a sense of
the enormous dimensions of the
combustion engine at station 3 the quad
turbo engine draws its power from the
ignition of a fuel air mixture these
camshafts ensure the correct mixing
ratio driven by the engines chain the
cams rotate around their metal shaft and
thereby press alternately on the valves
of the individual cylinder heads
this enables them to open and close in a
specific stroke the mechanics bolt two
of these 1 kilogram engine components
per cylinder Bank
the w16 engine in the Sheeran has a
total of four camshafts so that the
mixture can ignite the engineers now
insert sixteen spark plugs into the
cylinders they supply the final pulse
for starting the engine they also
influence the four-stroke engines
performance consumption and pollutant
emissions the plugs generate a powerful
spark between 500 and 3500 times a
minute the resulting explosions set the
ranks of pistons in the cylinder bank in
motion
the stripped engine meaning all of the
components needed to operate the drive
unit is now complete
however the massive power plant is
considerably bigger when fully assembled
all further attaching parts are true to
the Bugatti philosophy of more power and
maximum performance the final dimensions
of the engine in a Sheeran are four
times those of a standard passenger car
engine
[Music]
since 2005 the engines for the French
luxury brand have been hand-built at the
plant in Zod's katha even when the
company was founded in 1909 the engine
blocks were cast by hand at Bugatti back
then the engines for the first models
were produced at the plant premises in
Molsheim although working conditions 110
years ago were certainly tougher the
basic structure of high-performance
engines has barely changed with his
racing and luxury cars the Milan born
company founder was considered to be a
legend of European automobile history
even back then
[Music]
at eight order Bugatti developed and
built vehicles that are still icons of
motoring history today cars like the t35
with the bugatti atlantic ettore bugatti
was a perfectionist and did incredible
things here in this plant back in the
20s and 30s the simple fact that we call
our plant an atelier rather than a
factory is quite a statement in itself
the entire mole time site here in Alsace
France is unique for an automotive
manufacturer because it exudes pure
history and no other manufacturer can
offer that
the name Bugatti stood for revolutionary
ideas from the get-go
in 1933 the Milan born visionary even
built a rail bus with a top speed of 200
kilometers an hour a tour day was often
laughed at for his unconventional ideas
but in the 1920s Bugatti super sports
cars achieved worldwide fame thanks
above all to their record number of 2000
race victories
the name Sheeran also played a role back
then
cheval sharone was a racing driver in
the 1920s a very successful one we won a
lot of races with him buddies today the
bugatti chiron named after him as the
ultimate hyper sports car and the engine
is at the heart of it an eight liter
engine with 16 cylinders and up to 1600
horsepower
however the objective of building the
world's fastest production sports car in
the form of the new Sheeran was viewed
very critically by the industry gun
severity the whole world said you'll
never manage to cram so much power in a
car but a displacement of 8 liters over
a thousand horsepower as a conventional
task you had turbochargers to it at some
point you achieve that power and then
you're faced with a big problem you
can't find a test bench anywhere in the
world that can cope with this power but
the engineers solved precisely this
problem on an internally developed test
and they put the eight liter engine
through its paces until the manifold
glows
once completed the engineers test the
power output and above all the
durability of each power plant behind
the roughly 30 centimeter thick safety
walls of the test booth
the team has strapped the combustion
engine down and coupled it to a
dynamometer it's able to demand the
engines full output of 1500 horsepower
at 6700 revolutions per minute the
stress applied on the test bench is
significantly higher than during vehicle
operation an engine is tortured for up
to 1,000 hours on the test bench the sin
fee that's hundreds of thousands of
kilometers on the road and what if an
engine has survived that can survive
anything
a gigantic blower cools the engine
during the test special sensors measure
a total of five hundred different values
which the testers check on the monitor
the tests were also an important part of
developing the 16 cylinder engine
because the results were incorporated
into its 3d model and helped the design
engineers to detect possible critical
areas it took three years to develop the
Sheeran's power plant often optimization
requirements also arise due to legal
specifications corresponding measures
that the engineers plan on their screens
then have to be verified on the real
component during a special auditory test
an acoustic engineer checks whether the
exhaust system simulation matches
reality to do this the sound expert
applies a pure tone to the exhaust
tailpipes using a loudspeaker the sound
causes the air particles inside the
system to vibrate the engineer records
the resonance using a microphone this
allows the sound and the volume to be
viewed on the monitor by 2026 passenger
car driving noises have to be reduced to
68 decibels that's roughly the same as a
television at low volume at the same
time however the engine sound must not
suffer the acoustic factors are
particularly crucial to the experience
of driving the Sheeran
that's what the drivers hearing is an
entirely unconscious process it's
nevertheless he needs specific
information he wants to know when the
road changes he wants to know whether
the engine rpm is too low or too high he
wants to know what the absolute vehicle
speed is because via the wind noises if
any of this information is missing the
vehicle is perceived as unharmonious
[Music]
does her galoshes cliff the rolling
noise is relevant how the windows are
constructed how well the chassis is
insulated from the cockpit just because
all of this characterizes the overall
noise perceived by the driver this all
has to be composed to form a consistent
concert to achieve a positive experience
in the vehicles interior and who better
to test this experience in new models
than a genuine motor racing expert the
former LeMond
winner Andy Wallace is Bugattis test
driver he has already driven around
100,000 kilometers in the luxury sports
car from multi I'm an absolute dream job
the Briton also provides the developers
with direct feedback about the Sheeran's
performance and handling from the
driver's cockpit if he like cars and you
you can maybe dream about supercars this
one is the top the very top of the pile
[Music]
and for me to be able to drive this car
every day if you told me that when I was
seven years old I never would have
believed you so for me it's fantastic
however Wallace will be thinking about
the following drive for a long time to
come with this sheer on the Britain will
set a new speed record of three hundred
and four point seven seven three miles
an hour or four hundred and ninety point
four eight four kilometers an hour
the Sheeran's Super Sport 300 plus
pre-production model offers an
additional 100 horsepower totaling 1600
horsepower on the test track in ela
lesson Germany its tires will be
rotating no fewer than 4,000 100 times
per minute this would be the first time
in history that a production vehicle
breaks the 300 mile an hour barrier
and off he goes Andy Wallace floors the
accelerator and is already doing 100
kilometres an hour two seconds later
covering around 11 square kilometers the
test site lies at the center of a pine
forest curves and straights follow in
quick succession this makes it difficult
to keep the vehicle on track you're
constantly turning to go straight and
this is at the same time that you're
traveling 136 meters per second
everything's coming at you really really
quick so the sense is coming in - you
are crazy and you have to try and keep
all that under control and then it's not
something you do every day so it's not
something you can practice you just end
up doing it and it's um it's pretty
impressive 3.5 kilometers ahead of the
record the Sheeran is still picking up
speed the down thrust also called
downforce on its rear end increases this
causes the front end to lift the Bugatti
uses a complicated aerodynamics concept
to counteract the principle that helps
airplanes to take off after 70 seconds
at full throttle Wallis breaks the
record
Wow guys what a fantastic car thank you
should fancy a messy I can't thank you
enough
[Music]
in the Atelier in Molsheim France a
worker transports an important component
to a newly arrived engine block two
mechanics now coupled this seven-speed
direct-shift transmission to the
powerplant
the automatic shift unit ensures
constant power output when shifting
gears because one clutch closes at the
same time as the other is opening the
automatic transmission ensures
consistent tractive force the workers
then take the new drive unit to an
assembly station covering 1,000 square
meters the shop is more akin to a
sterile operating room than a vehicle
workshop there are no oil stains or
rubber abrasion from car tires on the
highly polished synthetic resin floor
the two-seaters engine alone costs
around 300 thousand euros
over the next few hours the rear section
of the vehicle will be built around the
high performance unit to do this the
Bugatti surgeons first attached the
chassis to the side sections of the body
alongside the lifting platform they are
also made entirely of carbon a
technician first bolts the independent
wheel suspension elements to the carbon
fiber framework the hypercar has no
rigid axle this means that each wheel
can be actuated individually and
therefore has maximum grip or contact
surface on the asphalt as a result the
two-ton Bugatti remains stable even when
taking tight corners on a wet road
surface depending on the driving
situation the on-board computer
regulates the four wheels tow and camber
to ensure this
the entire substructure of the extreme
sports car is adaptive these suspension
struts that the technician is installing
can also be optionally set to a family
car or racing car profile the hardness
of the damper called its characteristic
and technician jargon is adjusted by
allowing more or less oil to flow from
one shock absorber tube to the other
[Music]
the worker now mounts the finished side
section on the engine block with his
colleague building a new hyper car in
the exclusive French manufactory is
complicated and involves 2590 individual
steps good timing in the production
sequence is absolutely crucial
I'm apologizing we always assemble
sixteen vehicles at the same time using
twenty employees these includes seven
mechanics for coachbuilders three
technicians you assemble the vehicle
interior two painters and for
electricians don't gloss on without this
team of twenty persons assembles the
vehicle in eight weeks visa man this
needs to be well organized to avoid
delays and ensure that the customers are
satisfied yeah next the supercar is
fitted with its exhaust system when the
engine is running temperatures as high
as 500 degrees can be reached at the
rear muffler that's why this employee
first installs a galvanized heat shield
on the exhaust pipes his colleague
carries the gigantic exhaust to the
chassis
later on six tailpipes rid the Sheerin
of everything the eight liter powerplant
spits out of its 16 cylinders
the team now fastens the enormous
titanium muffler to the rear end of the
emerging Bugatti titanium is light
ductile and particularly heat resistant
this is important so that the material
does not crack under the extreme heat
the crew then clads the mid engine with
further elements to protect it on all
sides
tons of them too we've now fitted all
the parts around the engine and once
we've assembled bolted and connected
everything we can connect it to the
front section to the monocoque this is
what distinguishes us from classic
mechanics and garage
this really is assembly we start with
nothing and build the vehicle and that
is the difference between this and other
vehicles because this is an exclusive
card extremely powerful vehicles you
have to work very precisely you can't
afford to make mistakes it's now
becoming cramped in the monocoque - such
a cockpit framework contains a total of
320 square meters of carbon placed end
to end all of the individual carbon
fibers are 9 times the distance from the
earth to the moon a mechanic is now
fitting one of the Sheeran's two
differentials on the underbody of the
chassis element a computer tells him
whether he has tightened all of the
bolts to the correct torque and stores
his production data in the system
the differential compensates the
differences in wheel speeds when
cornering the wheels on the inner side
of a corner cover a shorter distance
than the outer wheels and therefore
turned more slowly conversely this means
that the outer wheels require more power
to cover the greater distance in the
same time a transmission inside the
differential distributes the engines
power to the hypercars individual wheels
to varying degrees
bringing the vehicle to a stop from its
top speed of 420 kilometers an hour
poses a major challenge for the brake
system the temperature can soar to 1,100
degrees when the supercar is braked
that's as hot as glowing lava the men in
the Atelier therefore also fit a heat
shield on the wheel suspension before
installing the carbon ceramic brake
discs one of the sport brake discs
weighs around eight point five kilograms
its caliper is the world's largest 3d
printed titanium part
the Sheerin currently has the most
powerful brakes of any production
vehicle worldwide but this is not enough
for the French 1/2 here a design model
of a brake saddle that we don't have in
production yet but we're testing it
where you see material on this part
that's where the the load path is
happening and that's where the the
strength needs to be on this building
part and where there is no material at
all there's also no load on the part
that means you can save that weight
it doesn't need any styling lines but
just the pure genius of the technical
development is aesthetically so
interesting and so intriguing that you
leave well enough alone and apply it to
the car and this is really fascinating
in itself the bugatti crew assembles the
front of the monocoque this worker is
fitting a guard for the Sheeran's
sensitive electronics and mounting a
control unit for controlling the vehicle
dynamics later on this so-called ESC
helps the driver to keep the hypercar
under control
by specifically breaking individual
wheels for instance the system prevents
the vehicle from skidding when cornering
at high speed over a period of four days
the team has installed 2600 components
at the special stations an important
ceremony is now on the agenda for the
front and rear frames like everything at
Bugatti the marriage of the monocoque
and the rear section in the mall team
luxury Atelier is something special the
crew first moves the platform's to the
same height the frame sections have to
fit precisely in one another in the
worst case the construction would have
to be taken apart again to adjust
individual elements
the three men now maneuver the 750
kilogram rear section to the monocoque
the iron wave accompanies the rear
section to its better half the team
gathers its strength again for the last
few centimetres the fact that the
Sheeran's chassis consists of two parts
offers several advantages so that the
driver's cockpit is subsequently stable
and therefore as safe as possible the
front section is made completely of
carbon however the entire body is too
big to be built entirely of this
lightweight material the vehicle is also
designed so that the rear end can tear
off in the event of an accident because
if the engine catches fire things
quickly become dangerous a total of
fourteen titanium bolts that the
technicians are now fastening ensure
that the front and rear sections are
joined firmly together
on the underbody to Bugatti mechanics
now fasten the lines for the luxury cars
operating fluids later on engine and
transmission oil as well as brake fluid
will flow through them the Sheeran's
fuel hoses are made of tough polyamide
plastic the air stream at the front end
of the vehicle ends up in these two
carbon chambers via special filters it
flows into the four turbochargers
compressors where it is then forced into
the cylinders and increased pressure
this means that there is more air and
therefore more oxygen for combusting the
fuel the result is a more powerful
explosion higher pressure and thus
linear engine power output the Bugatti
special tires are custom products from
Michelin with a width of around 36
centimeters the tires have to withstand
enormous forces during vehicle operation
at maximum speed the wheels rotate
around 50 times per second this means
that 7 metric tonnes are pulling on
their tread that tortures the tough
rubber the Sheerin is fitted with semi
slicks they have a lower tread depth and
therefore less weight as a result the
tires offer plenty of grip despite the
enormous centrifugal forces a set of the
semi slicks costs nine thousand two
hundred and fifty euros the hyper car is
now filled with its operating fluids an
employee feeds the vehicle with engine
oil brake fluid and 40 litres of water
when the car is driving this is
circulated 20 times per minute by the
pump to prevent the engine and
powertrain from overheating the mechanic
then fills the hypercars tank the fuel
tank can hold 100 litres of gasoline the
shiron consumes an average of 20 2.5
litres every 100 kilometers
the Bugattis rolling chassis now
proceeds to its first test station in
the Antilles annex the French had to
develop a new dynamometer for the
sheeran which is capable of withstanding
the hypercars 1,500 horsepower this
means that the bugatti dynamometer is
also the most powerful of its kind in
the world
the technician first attaches the
two-ton vehicle to these wheel clamps
the safety flap of the acceleration
roller then drops down and the
ventilation system shafts rise up then
he fastens a fresh air hose to the front
of the chassis so that he doesn't
suffocate in the cockpit his colleagues
have provisionally fitted a windshield
in the luxury car the technician now
also fits two doors to establish the
most realistic conditions possible in
the vehicle interior now the high
performance car can show what it's made
of for the first time
the employee accelerates up to 200
kilometres an hour the sports car has to
complete a total of 342 tests he tests
the engine the transmission and all
vehicle dynamics programs for 3 hours
the bugatti covers around 60 kilometers
on the dynamometer this Sheeran has
passed all of the tests the employee
releases the vehicle from the wheel
clamps and removes the doors his
colleague now takes this superlative on
wheels to the next station
here the Sheeran is dressed in its
Sunday best to do this the exterior crew
pre assembles the body parts next to the
lifting columns and cleans and polishes
them the individual elements are large
and fragile that makes this work step
extremely demanding we get parts that
are perfectly painted and absolutely
flawless
[Music]
a pesky can be what is then complicated
for us is to install these parts without
damaging them that's not easy we have to
take great care work very precisely and
attach the part so that everything is
perfect for the final quality check and
the customers ultimately satisfied it
takes up to four days to clothe the
vehicle installing the windshield is
particularly complicated it has to be
positioned exactly and be absolutely
watertight to install the windshield the
technicians first coat the body with a
primer they apply a special adhesive
onto the safety glass
the workers then place the windshield
onto the vehicle frame using a vacuum
lifter the two component mixture reacts
to form a particularly elastic resin and
ensures that the glass can withstand
even strong vibrations each Sheerin is a
unique work of art and can be completely
individualized the choice of material
and color combinations for styling the
vehicle is virtually unlimited
Ettore Bugatti himself once said
perfection is never achieved but to this
very day designers have been attempting
to create the most perfect models with a
mixture of unbridled power technical
beauty and flawless elegance to
accomplish this they work closely with
the developers because the paramount
objective of motorsport artists is form
follows performance the striking see of
the Bugatti DNA on both of the Sheeran's
flanks therefore also serves a specific
purpose to a lot of people that line
looks like a stylistic idea of a
designer or because it looks so nice and
romantic let's just do it like that it's
exactly the opposite the performance
need from the engineer was as much air
intake along the whole body side of the
car was needed to feed all that
pressured air into the engine
compartment for cooling purposes and for
me that is always the most authentic way
as a car designer that I can answer the
need of a technical problem with a
stylistic combination Bugattis vehicle
DNA has constantly evolved according to
this principle due to its shape the
exclusive Koopas extraordinary radiator
grille has been nicknamed the horseshoe
in 1910 however the first Bugatti model
the type 13 had an egg-shaped front end
to improve the vehicles aerodynamics and
cool the increasingly larger engine the
designers adapted the look of the grille
to the technical requirements probably
the only part of a bugatti whose shape
or weight has not been optimized is the
brand logo this sheer on in the Atelier
in mall time is now almost fully dressed
each paneling element also plays a role
in the complex aerodynamics this
consists of active and passive systems
all of the components integrated into
the paneling are passive the active
modules can be actuated and adjusted to
the position and speed of the vehicle
the super sports car is a master of
aerodynamics the air curtains at the
front specifically guide the impacting
air pressure through and past the
vehicle this presses the Sheerin onto
the asphalt and cools the brakes
[Music]
the 1.5 meter wide rear spoiler adapts
fully automatically to the respective
driving situation 0.8 seconds after
applying the brakes the adaptive wing
tilts to an angle of 49 degrees thus
acting as an extremely effective air
brake to decelerate the Bugatti the
hydraulic spoiler is the last of a total
of 55 panel parts that the mechanics fit
onto the luxury car we regulate the
angular position of the rear wing the
diffuser flaps in the underbody via the
speed range
this is how we ensure that the vehicle
is safe in every driving situation and
that the focus is on straight-line
stability or agility
in 2017 the airbrake played an important
role in another world record formula one
winner
juan pablo montoya accelerated the
Sheerin to four hundred kilometers an
hour from a standing start after 700
meters he was already doing over 300
kilometres an hour in the 33rd second
the Colombian racing driver reached the
400 kilometer an hour mark
he brought the two-ton vehicle to a
standstill again after 491 meters in
just nine point three seconds by fully
applying the brakes Montoya
took exactly 41.96 seconds and covered a
distance of 3.1 kilometers to accelerate
the Sheerin up to its top speed and
break it that was a new world record so
far no other vehicle has managed to
achieve this outstanding performance
a force of 850 kilograms presses on the
rear wing during maximum braking from
top speed
this brings the hypercars rear axle to
its knees
during this sharp breaking maneuver
forces of around 2g act on the vehicle
and the driver
a further shiron has now been fully
assembled at the Bugatti premises in
multi France so that it's not scratched
during its first test-drive the employee
is covering each millimeter of the hyper
sports car with a protective film
covering the paneling takes around four
hours
this supercar has been fully covered
later on it will demonstrate what it's
capable of
each Sheeran has to complete a
test-drive of around 350 kilometers
before being delivered we do the test
drives with a protective film in the car
on the windshield it takes half a day to
cover the sharone with film but it's up
to us not to damage the car under any
circumstances we want to deliver a
perfect vehicle over these 350
kilometers we simulate all the driving
situations that the customer might
encounter villages country roads
mountains freeways and of course we have
rented the airfield in Colmar to test
everything that's not allowed on public
roads only then can the customers safely
drive the vehicle at its top speed of
400 km/h so that he can do that the
quality tester now climbs into the
driver's seat for around 5 hours the
cockpit is also fitted with protective
covers the tester additionally wears
gloves so that no marks are left on the
sports steering wheel
the tester tests different factors such
as performance the individual drive
programs and the background noise in the
interior of the Sheeran before leather
seats so much as squeaks when cornering
the test driver notes this defect in his
log the tester then turns onto an
airfield here he immediately takes the
Sheerin up to its limits he communicates
with the tower crew by radio because air
traffic is still operating and that can
quickly become hazardous the stormy
weather also makes conditions more
difficult the test driver quickly drives
up to the start of the 1.6 kilometer
long takeoff runway then he's given the
green light from the tower the expert
hits the accelerator
he accelerates the hypercar up to 300
kilometres an hour in around 13 seconds
however the primary objective is not to
test the top speed but to get the shear
on to develop its full output of 1500
horsepower due to safety reasons the
sports car is governed to 380 kilometres
an hour
this special key can be used to
accelerate it a further 40 kilometres an
hour as soon as the high speed key is
engaged on the left of the driver's seat
the vehicle checks all of its systems
fully automatically because at over 400
kilometres an hour
any defect can immediately prove to be
fatal the shear on is wonderful to drive
it is incredibly stable when you switch
from left to right its chassis is also
fantastic in response to any road
conditions like a dream as if you were
skiing after the stress tests the shear
on is taken to the company's own washing
facility the hypercar can only be
delivered to its new owner when it's
absolutely spotless
bugatti the french sports car
menufactory is an absolute superlative
at 12 high-end production stations in
mul time 20 elite mechanics produce the
fastest most exquisite and most extreme
hyper cars in the world with multiple
world records the french extremists have
proved and if it's comparable if it's no
longer bugatti after even more than 110
years of vehicle production nothing
about this philosophy has changed